Hello friends welcome to the channel today we
will understand that HDFC Life is
falling and what should term investors do
because HDFC Life
is currently in its 2nd year loop and this budget talk, there has been a
huge fall in the stock, the
stock fell by 18% in a single day so watch this video
till the end if you are invested or
you are thinking of investing because this
video will be very important for you if
you are new to this channel please
subscribe let's start the video
HDFC Life is a joint venture between HDFC
and HDFC Life. It is an investment
company in Scotland UK it offers a
range of life insurance plans such as
term insurance plans health insurance
child education insurance lips and many
pension products there is an
industry and there are many
competitors in this space in this space the
first region is
impacted the bottom line of this component
in simple words the company has settled a lot of claims
due to which there has been a
huge impact on the profitability in effect this is the second one every life
insurance company has faced  The
budget announced in February, where
earlier a tax rebate or taxation was available on premiums above Rs 5 lakh, will
no longer be available. In India, people
still view insurance as a tax-saving
product. This is
actually a good step in the long term
where the entire industry will have to revamp
and sell their products. Earlier, they used to
push their products in the market as a tax-saving tool, which will
now reduce. Because of this announcement, the
Managing Director of
HDFC Life has given guidance that there would be an
impact of 10 to 12% on their
revenue and a 5% impact
on their profitability. The
last reason for the fall of the stock is
lower than the expected results. Now we
will review the operational and financial metrics of the company. Let's see
how has been the past performance of this company.
HDFC Life has a market share of 9% in
new business premium. First of all, let's
understand what a new business is.
So, they buy insurance products,
for example.  If you buy term insurance,
you pay the premium, correct
premium, and they pay yours,
correct. So, new business premium is
where the company sells its products
and the first premium comes from there.
Date is new business premium, there they have a
market share of 9%. Let's
talk about these metrics which are
important in evaluating an insurance company. The first one is new
business performance. I told you what
new business is. If you
look here in January 2018, the company had a
revenue of around Rs 1000 crore and
now it has jumped to around Rs 2300 crore.
This jump from date is
18% per year. The company has been growing 18% year on year
in the last 5 years. Now
we see what is the company's ratio from 61 month bus
stand. Before that, it is
important to understand what is persistence ratio.
So, the meaning of persistence ratio is that suppose that
you  You buy insurance
and you pay its premium every year,
this means how many customers are there
who are paying premium even after 61 months, that means
their premium is increasing even after 5 years because
here the company does not have to do any extra work to
acquire customers
and there is no additional cost for them, the
entire profit of the
premium is converted into profit only,
hence located here, the interest number in 2016 was
37%, but
today the persistency ratio has increased to
around 50%, that is a very
good sign, now let's look at the
embedded value for this company, now first of all we have to
know what is embedded value,
I explained to you that
we pay premium, okay, if
my company sells a policy, the
revenue of the product sold, which
comes every year, correct value is basically
a present value of future  If we look at the profit which is
their future premium, it has
increased to more than ₹30,000 crore as of today, out of which
more than ₹37,000 crore and this growth is fine,
this is growth.
Now if we look at our last
metric, it has also grown very rapidly,
from around ₹2,500 crore, today it is above ₹2
lakh crore. Here also the growth has been
20% year on year.
From ₹67,000 crore to ₹2 crore, the
company which is managing it today, so the growth here is
18%, 23%, 20%, which makes us understand
that the insurance industry
is a very growing sector in India and
is also under-premised and this sector will
grow to 3X in the coming years.
Now we look at the profit capability of the company
because if you will look at the profit of this
company, which has grown massively over a
period of time, which was around ₹400 crore in 2013.
And today it has crossed Rs 1000 crore. The
profit after tax, of which the net profit is
from Rs 450 crore to Rs 1200 crore today, which
we have seen a jump of almost 3x
from 2013.
And here in
one person, there is no growth at all
and the reason is because the
industry is very under-penetrated
in India. There is a lot of room for growth,
particularly not for this stock, but
many companies are doing business in this sector.
So, here the main reason is for HDFC
Life Insurance stock
and other budgets. And both of these are temporary in
nature. The penetration of insurance in
India will come to a close. And
healthcare in India is becoming very expensive.
You can see that there is a huge
difference between the cost that used to be there earlier and what it is now.
Insurance is a highly profitable business
with not much overhead. I had explained this to you
through 61 month persistence
ratio. Here the company is
getting revenue without any effort through premium. If
you are a little patient in the stock, it will
Definitely, come back now, what should we do in the stock,
so here I am giving you
things, here there is a short term, medium term
and a long term, so I am
particularly Bhuleshvar, long term and I
see this entire sector here for seven to 10 years,
this would be a
consistent compounder trust, because this
entire business is
running crisply and HDFC Life
is trading it, in fact, its support
line has also been bridged after the budget,
I think it is a good time to make
entry in this particular stock, which
can give you a return of approximately 60%
if it achieves its previous high which is
774 and if other companies which are
fundamentally very good, are going at a
fast pace and are also profitable, they will
definitely breach their all-time high, so
if I look at it from a medium term perspective, which is three to five
years.  Raha Hai Wahan Pe Ye Stock
800 Touch Kar Saka
60% For Long Term Investors This Will Be A
Definite Consistent Compounder Gaas
Door Member Ok If You Invest Long Term
Date Is Not This It
Test Your Patience Learn To Sit Tight And Do Nothing
Same Time
In Long Topospective How To Find This
Content Interesting Please Like The Video
And Subscribe My Channel It Motivates Me To Do
Batore I Am Ashish Shining Of Thank You
So Much